<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xgboost on Modelling with R</title>
    <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/tags/xgboost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xgboost on Modelling with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/tags/xgboost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Episode 10: Animal adoption</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/animal_adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/animal_adoption/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe data for episode 10 of Sliced, the second round of the play-offs, relates to the adoption of abandoned or unwanted pets. Given information about the animal, such as its breed and age, the competitors had to predict a three class outcome, either, adoption, transfer or what is euphemistically called ‘no outcome’, which in reality means that the animal was put down (another euphemism).
The data can be downloaded from https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Episode 9: Baseball home runs</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/baseball/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/baseball/</guid>
      <description>SummaryBackground: In episode 9 of the 2021 series of Sliced, the competitors were given two hours in which to analyse a set of data on baseball. The aim was to predict whether or not a hit went for a home run.
My approach: I ran an extensive exploratory analysis relating the percentage of home runs to each of the exploratory factors. The type of hit is extremely predictive; for instance, you cannot hit a home run off a ground ball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Episode 7: Customer Churn</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/customer_churn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/customer_churn/</guid>
      <description>Summary:Background: In episode 7 of the 2021 series of Sliced, the competitors were given two hours in which to analyse a set of data on bank customers. The aim was to predict whether a customer would churn (leave the bank).
My approach: I started with the idea that people churn for different reasons and because of this, it will be difficult to find a single scale that distinguishes churners from non-churners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Episode 5: Airbnb Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/airbnb_prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/airbnb_prices/</guid>
      <description>Summary:Background: In episode 5 of the 2021 series of Sliced, the competitors were given two hours in which to analyse a set of data on Airbnb properties in New York City. The aim was to predict the price per night.
My approach: I work on a log(price + 1) scale as suggested by the evaluation metric. I spend quite a lot of time on feature extraction. I extract keywords from the description of the property and I merge geographically close neighbourhoods with few properties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
