<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>logistic regression on Modelling with R</title>
    <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/tags/logistic-regression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in logistic regression on Modelling with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/tags/logistic-regression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bayes Sliced 2: Wildlife Strikes</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/bayes_wildlife_strikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/bayes_wildlife_strikes/</guid>
      <description>Summary:Background: In episode 2 of the 2021 series of Sliced, the competitors were given two hours in which to analyse a set of data on wildlife strikes with aircraft. The aim was to predict whether or not the aircraft was damaged in the collision.
My approach: The database was created by the FAA from reports filed by pilots that are clearly incomplete. For my previous post, I spent the vast majority of the time cleaning the data and afterwards used a logistic regression model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Episode 4: Rain Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/rain_tomorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/rain_tomorrow/</guid>
      <description>Summary:Background: In episode 4 of the 2021 series of Sliced, the competitors were given two hours in which to analyse a set of data on daily weather patterns in different parts of Australia. The aim was to predict whether or not it will rain the next day.
My approach: I started with the idea that location would be key to a good model and I tried two approaches, one based on average rainfall patterns for the time of year and the other based on a day’s weather predicting the weather on the following day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliced Episode 2: Wildlife Strikes</title>
      <link>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/wildlife_strikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://modelling-with-r.netlify.app/wildlife_strikes/</guid>
      <description>Summary:Background: In episode 2 of the 2021 series of Sliced, the competitors were given two hours in which to analyse a set of data on wildlife strikes with aircraft. The aim was to predict whether or not the aircraft was damaged in the collision.
My approach: The original database was created by the FAA from reports filed by pilots and reporting is clearly incomplete. I spent the vast majority of my time cleaning the data and afterwards used a logistic regression model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
